<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sass on Joseph Rex&#39;s blog - Exploring Software, Food recipes, and Design</title>
    <link>https://josephrex.me/tags/sass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sass on Joseph Rex&#39;s blog - Exploring Software, Food recipes, and Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://josephrex.me/tags/sass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Enter Sass namespacing</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/enter-sass-namespacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/enter-sass-namespacing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sass has always been to me that one preprocessor that makes others not worth learning. I think stylus is quite okay but I&amp;rsquo;ve never used Less and I don&amp;rsquo;t even know if it is spelled LESS or Less but we&amp;rsquo;re not here to talk about less we are here to talk about more (pun intended). More features to the amazing Sass.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using source maps</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/using-source-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/using-source-maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;{% image mappings.png class=&amp;ldquo;head-image&amp;rdquo; alt=&amp;ldquo;source maps&amp;rdquo; %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web browser inspector plays a good role when debugging CSS. However, with the widespread of pre-processors now, we are faced with a challenge of debugging our CSS. Using a pre-processor like Sass, when you have your output style to be expanded or nested, this may not be much of a problem as you will almost get accurate debugging lines except if those lines had been separated by variables and mixins within your pre-processor stylesheet. In my case, I use the compressed (minified) output and I believe a lot of other developers do this to boost their pagespeed. This way, the whole of your compiled CSS stylesheet is on a single line and if you will try to debug for a line number, you will always find rule on line 1.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s wrong with Compass? Failed to watch due to inotify limit</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/whats-wrong-with-compass-failed-to-watch-due-to-inotify-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/whats-wrong-with-compass-failed-to-watch-due-to-inotify-limit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a [recent article][1], I talked about my OS migration. Changing Operating System is not an easy thing to go through but I went through it anyway. After setting up all I needed, I wanted to resume to my projects ASAP. I downloaded Sass and Compass again and pulled my project from it&amp;rsquo;s repository on an SVN. I tried &lt;code&gt;compass watch&lt;/code&gt; and I got an error like:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sass and Compass: My Best Friends</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/sass-and-compass-my-best-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/sass-and-compass-my-best-friends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a left-brained computer savvy. I love logic and math and because of this, I may be attracted to Sass not just because it&amp;rsquo;s awesome but also because it gives me a chance to keep my brain busy with logic. I think this picture speaks my state of mind right now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% image sass-tshirt-1.jpg alt=&amp;ldquo;sass-tshirt-1&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;ldquo;head-image&amp;rdquo; %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing Sass for 3 months now. I hope to give Stylus a try some time soon as I hear of it as another Super Hero Pre-processor. As of now, I don&amp;rsquo;t have any interest in writing LESS. This article is not about what I like or what I don&amp;rsquo;t like anyway.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging SASS for your front-end designs</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/leveraging-sass-for-your-front-end-designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/leveraging-sass-for-your-front-end-designs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I chose to move from vanilla CSS to the syntactically awesome stylesheeets and this has been a great step in my life. It&amp;rsquo;s like leaving a klingon which I&amp;rsquo;ve had as a girlfriend to date a human or vulcan :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Team-Sass&lt;/a&gt; provided a style guide for SASS concerning how we can name our variables for colors. A basic variable naming should be as it is on &lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/styleguide/color/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/styleguide/color/&#34;&gt;http://sass-lang.com/styleguide/color/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where all the colors have their names as variables like so:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh Sass! How awesome is it gonna get</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/sass-awesomeness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/sass-awesomeness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started writing Sass not too long ago and it has been one of the best experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had. Sass (Syntatically Awesome Stylesheet) is just as awesome as the name sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sass is a CSS predecessor that gives smart designers a lot more flexibility with the styling. New features are being added to Sass and with contributions of the Google team, it&amp;rsquo;s getting even faster than you can imagine. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-ZJeOJGazgE&#34;&gt;talk by Chris Eppstein&lt;/a&gt; reveals the work in progress.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>