<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Joseph Rex&#39;s blog - Exploring Software, Food recipes, and Design</title>
    <link>https://josephrex.me/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Joseph Rex&#39;s blog - Exploring Software, Food recipes, and Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://josephrex.me/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohesion against coupling</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/cohesion-against-coupling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/cohesion-against-coupling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coupling and Cohesion are two major principles for structured design in software. It&amp;rsquo;s commonly heard that high cohesion and low/loose coupling leads to good software design. Cohesion is an act of sticking together. In physics cohesion gets contrasted against adhesion as the sticking together of particles of the same substance where adhesion happens with dissimilar substances. With this in mind we know that any 2 things can be put together and we could assume a cohesive code.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using version managers and virtual environments</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/Using-version-managers-and-virtual-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/Using-version-managers-and-virtual-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a new year and 2015 was a blast for me. I successfully ticked every item on my list for 2015 and I had even more that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t expected from the start of the year.
In July, I got an email from &lt;a href=&#34;http://packtpub.com&#34;&gt;PacktPub&lt;/a&gt; about reviewing a book on building GUIs with Python. The opportunity was influenced by &lt;a href=&#34;http://josephrex.me/getting-started-with-gui-development-in-python/&#34;&gt;the article I&amp;rsquo;d written&lt;/a&gt; on the subject and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did. The book was completed and published in December and I got really excited to see that I&amp;rsquo;m a part of something that&amp;rsquo;ll impact the lives of people around the world. It is available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1785283758?keywords=python%20gui%20programming%20cookbook&amp;amp;qid=1451209838&amp;amp;ref_=sr_1_1&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.packtpub.com/application-development/python-gui-programming-cookbook&#34;&gt;PacktPub&lt;/a&gt; and I urge you to grab a copy as there&amp;rsquo;s so much to learn from it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating database password algorithm gracefully</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/migrating-database-password-algorithm-gracefully/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/migrating-database-password-algorithm-gracefully/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a developer that keeps up with the community and best practices you will often find bits of your code and process that needs improvement for security, scalibility, performance or whatsoever. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s not code you wrote but code that had been used in a company you find yourself. The situation here is to change the application&amp;rsquo;s users database encyption from that salted MD5 or SHA1 hash or even a non-salted integrity based hash to a hash that uses multiple rounds like bcrypt.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>