<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinions on Joseph Rex&#39;s blog - Exploring Software, Food recipes, and Design</title>
    <link>https://josephrex.me/tags/opinions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinions on Joseph Rex&#39;s blog - Exploring Software, Food recipes, and Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://josephrex.me/tags/opinions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CRIC: Confidence Reflex Intuition Consistency</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/cric/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/cric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went into the basketball court to play last week after a long time. That was maybe 2 years ago and the last time before that some other 2 years. There were a few times I&amp;rsquo;d gone and just made some hoops while a playing team is on a timeout but this time I really played and it was for just 10 minutes.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why go to college</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/why-go-to-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/why-go-to-college/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are in an era where knowledge has become so accessible that we question the need for higher education which was once known as the touchstone for professional excellence. Having so much data at our fingertips and knowing how to apply them is a great advantage of living in this century.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Semantic Styling vs Visual Styling</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/thoughts-on-semantic-styling-vs-visual-styling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/thoughts-on-semantic-styling-vs-visual-styling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After reading this &lt;a href=&#34;http://cssmojo.com/opinions_of_leaders_considered_harmful/&#34;&gt;rebuttal&lt;/a&gt; to Jeffrey Zeldman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeldman.com/2017/01/03/kiss-my-classname/&#34;&gt;Kiss my classname&lt;/a&gt; what came up on my mind is I think everyone&amp;rsquo;s doing this wrong. This is the main problem with the industry. Impatience to accept and learn why opinions that differ from yours could be relevant.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality against speed in development</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/quality-against-speed-in-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/quality-against-speed-in-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is common for humans to expect things to arrive almost as soon as they find the need for them. It starts from kids wanting their parents to get them their favorite toy from a toy store. A parent that tells the child we&amp;rsquo;ll have to come back next year for this toy will make the child unhappy at that moment.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What &#34;It&#39;s not about the money&#34; really means</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/what-its-not-about-the-money-really-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/what-its-not-about-the-money-really-means/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A female hacker</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/a-female-hacker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/a-female-hacker/</guid>
      <description>Men and Boys get so cocky sometimes that they are the only gender that have had the privilege to mess around computers from their young age. In this article, Crystal Beasley disproves that by sharing her nerd story.
http://skinnywhitegirl.com/blog/my-nerd-story/1101/
Plot twist: Paul Graham who was mentioned to have said women haven&amp;rsquo;t been hacking for long didn&amp;rsquo;t actually say that. Hear what he had to say:
http://paulgraham.com/wids.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appreciating developers</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/appreciating-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/appreciating-developers/</guid>
      <description>{% image appreciating-girl.jpg class=&#34;image image--wide&#34; alt=&#34;appreciating girl&#34; %}  We are all humans and appreciations are rewards that gladdens anyone. Some developers live a totally normal life. Especially those that have grown to build a family and have to keep them with love. On the other hand, there are a lot more melancholic developers that only find peace by dealing with complex logic. If a developer contributes to your project, start-up, firm, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter if they are still contributing or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not a perfectionist</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/im-not-a-perfectionist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/im-not-a-perfectionist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;{% image perfectionist-image.jpg alt=&amp;ldquo;perfectionist-image&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;ldquo;head-image&amp;rdquo; %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sick of hearing everyone call themselves perfectionists everywhere I go. Trust me, this is the most ridiculous thing you should call yourself from my view. I&amp;rsquo;d rather you use curse words on me than call me a perfectionist.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborated Projects are good and bad</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/collaborated-projects-are-good-and-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/collaborated-projects-are-good-and-bad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Project collaboration is one of the greatest things ever, especially in the open source community. Despite it&amp;rsquo;s awesomeness, there are always challenges in collaborated projects. Some idealist programmers pick up the code and find it uncomfortable to mix with non coordinated contributions by a clumsy programmer. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php-fig.org/psr/&#34;&gt;PSR&lt;/a&gt; exists in the PHP community to bring about ideas that may make good programmers follow some good concepts. This way, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a lot of similarity in the codes of various programmers that follow the PSR.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m an &#39;X&#39; programmer</title>
      <link>https://josephrex.me/im-an-x-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephrex.me/im-an-x-programmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All things programming is a part of hackery to me. I love to hack stuffs and that&amp;rsquo;s what has pulled me into the planet of development and engineering. From my observation, some people miss the point on what programming is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some see it as a tag to their beings like &amp;ldquo;Jake the Java Programmer&amp;rdquo;. What&amp;rsquo;s that? It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look reasonable to me. Not because I&amp;rsquo;m not a Java programmer but because it just isn&amp;rsquo;t right.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>